<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sysadmin on</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/tags/sysadmin/</link><description>Recent content in Sysadmin on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 16:49:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zacharyloeber.com/tags/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DevOps – Automating Kubernetes Deployments</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2018/09/28/devops-automating-kubernetes-deployments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 16:49:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2018/09/28/devops-automating-kubernetes-deployments/</guid><description>If you are deploying your own Kubernetes clusters you already know that:
Kubernetes is hard But there is hope!
There are a few great projects to keep an eye on in this space. I&amp;#8217;ve covered some of them in an article you can read on the Lumen.
Cheers!</description></item><item><title>Powershell: Creating Plaster Manifest Files</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2017/05/15/powershell-creating-plaster-manifest-files/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 17:49:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2017/05/15/powershell-creating-plaster-manifest-files/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve kicked the tires on a great PowerShell code scaffolding tool called &amp;#8216;Plaster&amp;#8217;. Here is my take on this nifty module.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShell: Azure ARM Site Overview</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2017/01/30/powershell-azure-arm-site-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 03:23:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2017/01/30/powershell-azure-arm-site-overview/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Visualizing an Azure deployment can be a bit tricky. This short Azure summary script is a good way to start though.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell: PSCloudflare Module</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2016/12/03/powershell-pscloudflare-module/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 16:27:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2016/12/03/powershell-pscloudflare-module/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A well documented API without a PowerShell Module is like an itch begging to be scratched.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell: New-ADPasswordReminder</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2016/10/13/powershell-new-adpasswordreminder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 19:03:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2016/10/13/powershell-new-adpasswordreminder/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A single, self-extracting, self-scheduling, AD password change notice PowerShell script.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShell: My Profile</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2016/05/04/powershell-my-profile/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 02:31:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2016/05/04/powershell-my-profile/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m always interested to see how other people setup their working environment or get things done. But rarely do I share my own environment. Since I&amp;#8217;m putting the effort into pushing my scripting environment publicly to github I may as well explain a bit more about some of what I&amp;#8217;ve setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PowerShell: Thoughts on Module Design</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/10/03/powershell-thoughts-on-module-design/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 18:57:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/10/03/powershell-thoughts-on-module-design/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve finally decided to grow up and start making modules out of my rather large PowerShell code base. Here are a few things I&amp;#8217;ve learned.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skype For Business: Planning for Voice – Part 3</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/09/12/skype-for-business-planning-for-voice-part-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 20:05:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/09/12/skype-for-business-planning-for-voice-part-3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following along this series you already know the importance of getting a recent PSTN provider bill and performing an onsite visit. Next we will go into more depth on how the site PSTN is configured with your PBX at a site. There is lots of ground to cover so lets dive right in!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skype For Business: Planning for Voice – Part 2</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/09/03/skype-for-business-planning-for-voice-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 03:18:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/09/03/skype-for-business-planning-for-voice-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve already gone over the basic phases of a Skype for Business enterprise voice deployment &lt;a href=&#34;https://zacharyloeber.com/2015/08/25/skype-for-business-planning-for-voice-part-1/&#34;&gt;in my prior article&lt;/a&gt;. Now it is time to skip right over the first two of those phases and start preparing to replace your existing PBXs. To prepare you need to know what you are going to be replacing. In this article we will be focusing on beginning the information gathering process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exchange: Database Leveling Redux</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/04/06/exchange-database-leveling-redux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 00:12:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/04/06/exchange-database-leveling-redux/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago I &lt;a href=&#34;https://zacharyloeber.com/2014/01/07/exchange-20102013-database-leveling-script/&#34;&gt;tackled the challenge&lt;/a&gt; of constructing a variant of the bin packing algorithm for leveling out Exchange databases&amp;#8217; size with the least amount of mailbox migrations necessary. Since then, I&amp;#8217;ve been approached by a few people in dreadfully large environments looking for help with errors and compatibility issues around the script I released. I&amp;#8217;ve finally rounded back to this script to do it some justice.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell: WPF/Treeview OU Selection Dialog</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/03/22/powershell-wpftreeview-ou-selection-dialog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 16:13:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/03/22/powershell-wpftreeview-ou-selection-dialog/</guid><description>&lt;p class=&#34;projectSummary&#34;&gt;
This is a self-contained organizational unit selection dialog box using powershell, xaml, wpf, and ADSI. Should be useful in any number of one off Powershell projects I imagine.
&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lync Book Review: Lync Server Cookbook</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/03/14/lync-book-review-lync-server-cookbook/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 01:51:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2015/03/14/lync-book-review-lync-server-cookbook/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I had planned to purchase this book at some point but instead was pleasantly surprised by an offer from one of the authors to provide an objective review of &amp;#8216;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Lync-Server-Cookbook-Fabrizio-Volpe-ebook/dp/B00SVBFBQS/ref=dp_kinw_strp_1&#34;&gt;Lync Server Cookbook&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;! As I have worked with the product in some form since LCS/OCS days I believe I can speak with some authority on subject matter and readily agreed. With that being said, lets start with the book&amp;#8217;s overarching scope and structure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell: Check For Misplaced Certificates</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/12/10/powershell-check-for-misplaced-certificates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 03:02:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/12/10/powershell-check-for-misplaced-certificates/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a script I absentmindedly put together one evening while power watching a TV series on Netflix with the wife. The general idea of this script is to check local machine, trusted root, and intermediate trusted root stores for misplaced or duplicate certificates.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2013: Server Component State Script</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/12/08/exchange-2013-server-component-state-script/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 01:28:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/12/08/exchange-2013-server-component-state-script/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Exchange 2013 includes some powershell commands which allow you to set and view several components in the messaging infrastructure. This is important to be aware of as it means all Exchange related services can be running when looking at them in service manager (services.msc) but not actually doing anything. I went ahead put together a script to better gather this information for administrators.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lync and UM Correlation with Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/11/13/lync-and-um-correlation-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 03:31:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/11/13/lync-and-um-correlation-with-powershell/</guid><description>I&amp;#8217;ve been working on an Exchange/Lync voice deployment lately and have found a new level of frustration for the lack of connectivity between the several voice components involved in turning up such a solution. That being said it is not very difficult to validate your deployment with a bit of Powershell.
There are a few necessary results to gather where I believe it can be easy to &amp;#8216;miss&amp;#8217; configuration steps when turning up or disabling users:</description></item><item><title>Exchange: Handling Old Log and Other Files</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/09/26/exchange-handling-old-log-and-other-files/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 19:41:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/09/26/exchange-handling-old-log-and-other-files/</guid><description>In Exchange old logs can really build up fast. Not database transaction logs but rather temporary transport, client access, IIS, and other debug related crap that typically default to locations either on your system drive or Exchange install path. Of course, Powershell scripting can provide a decent solution for this problem.
Introduction More than any other version, Exchange 2013 seems to like logging information to disk. By default, much of what gets logged will not auto-rotate (or if it does, it happens infrequently) either so you end up with this slow ticking time-bomb in your environment.</description></item><item><title>Powershell GUI Script Wrapper Utility</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/02/02/powershell-gui-script-wrapper-utility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 03:32:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/02/02/powershell-gui-script-wrapper-utility/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Creating GUIs for your scripts can be a tedious process. That is why I don’t do so for each powershell project I release. Instead of wasting my precious little free time putting together yet another GUI for a one off script I decided to create a tool which will create the GUI scripts for me automatically!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2010/2013: Database Leveling Script</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/01/07/exchange-20102013-database-leveling-script/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 22:08:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2014/01/07/exchange-20102013-database-leveling-script/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It is common to randomly choose mailbox databases when creating or migrating user mailboxes in Exchange. I actually recommend this practice unless you are setting up a tiered user/storage environment. Unfortunately this may result in an unequal distribution of data which, in turn, can result in an environment where mailbox databases are wildly different in size. In this post I will discuss an approach to leveling the databases so they are equal in size by moving mailboxes between them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gather (and Diagram) Installed Roles and Features With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/12/18/gather-and-diagram-installed-roles-and-features-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 18:53:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/12/18/gather-and-diagram-installed-roles-and-features-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Use this powershell script to gather installed features and roles from remote systems. This uses two wmi classes in an attempt to gather as much information as possible. Win32_ServerFeature will contain roles and their dependencies on systems running Windows 2008 and above. For these systems we can use this hierarchy to also produce pretty diagrams using graphviz and techniques I&amp;#8217;ve exhibited in some of my other scripts (I added this last part in cause it is easy to do, not really certain how useful it is other than maybe exploring the dependencies between windows roles/features).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gather Remote Event Logs With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/10/16/gather-remote-event-logs-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2013 17:01:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/10/16/gather-remote-event-logs-with-powershell/</guid><description>About Gather the remote event log information for one or more systems using wmi, alternate credentials, and multiple runspaces. Function supports custom timeout parameters in case of wmi problems and returns Event Log information for the specified number of past hours. You can view verbose information on each runspace thread in realtime with the -Verbose option.
Version History 1.0.0 &amp;#8211; 10/16/2013
Initial release Notes By default 24 hours is what we filter against for the results.</description></item><item><title>Retrieve Remote Scheduled Task Information With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/10/06/retrieve-remote-scheduled-task-information-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 23:32:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/10/06/retrieve-remote-scheduled-task-information-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This function uses multiple runspaces with along with COM objects to gather information about the scheduled tasks of remote systems. Getting this to work with alternate credentials may be possible but I wasn’t able to discern a usable method to make it happen so I resorted to PSremoting. What this means is that this script will work against multiple remote systems which do not have psremoting enabled as long as you are running the script with an account that has administrative rights to them. If you do pass a credential to the function then psremoting will be used instead. You can also force psremoting to be used if you are using that across the board in your environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Visualize Active Directory Site Connections</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/10/06/visualize-active-directory-site-connections/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 22:50:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/10/06/visualize-active-directory-site-connections/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;span-style-color-bbbbbb-font-size-12px-font-weight-normal-line-height-1-6-in-this-post-i-use-powershell-with-graphviz-to-create-an-active-directory-diagram-of-all-site-connections-between-servers-additionally-i-ve-included-some-code-which-displays-site-connection-options-you-may-be-able-to-use-this-to-find-isolated-dcs-or-just-to-see-a-pretty-diagram-span&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color: #bbbbbb; font-size: 12px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.6;&#34;&gt;In this post I use powershell with graphviz to create an Active Directory diagram of all site connections between servers. Additionally, I’ve included some code which displays site connection options. You may be able to use this to find isolated DCs or just to see a pretty diagram.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gather Remote Command Results With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/09/19/gather-remote-command-results-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 16:22:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/09/19/gather-remote-command-results-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Send a remote command using wmi, alternate credentials, and multiple runspaces then retrieve the results serially using mapped secure channels to the remote host. The remote command execution function supports custom timeout parameters in case of wmi problems and returns the remote tmp file information containing the command results. You can view verbose information on each runspace thread in realtime with the -Verbose option.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Get Remote Shadow Volume Information With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/09/14/get-remote-shadow-volume-information-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2013 02:57:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/09/14/get-remote-shadow-volume-information-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Gather the remote shadow volume information for one or more systems using wmi, alternate credentials, and multiple runspaces. Function supports custom timeout parameters in case of wmi problems and returns shadow volume information, shadow copies, their providers, and settings. You can view verbose information on each runspace thread in realtime with the -Verbose option.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gather Local Group Membership With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/09/11/gather-local-group-membership-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 14:11:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/09/11/gather-local-group-membership-with-powershell/</guid><description>Gather system local groups and their members for one or more systems using wmi, alternate credentials, and multiple runspaces. Function supports custom timeout parameters in case of wmi problems, a switch for inclusion of empty groups in the results, and returns group names with their members. You can view verbose information on each runspace thread in realtime with the -Verbose option.
Version History 1.0.0 &amp;#8211; 09/11/2013
Initial release Notes None, this is an independent release of a function I’ve recently included in a larger project.</description></item><item><title>Excel and HTML Asset Reports With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/09/08/excel-and-html-asset-reports-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 05:07:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/09/08/excel-and-html-asset-reports-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This set of powershell functions collates and generates reports upon system information it gathers. Information gathered includes hardware health, system information, networking information and much much more. Multiple types of html reports can be generated and all data can be exported directly to an excel workbook, saved as individual reports, and emailed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gather Remote Installed Programs With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/08/28/gather-remote-installed-programs-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 13:25:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/08/28/gather-remote-installed-programs-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 1.6;&#34;&gt;Gather program install information for one or more systems using wmi, alternate credentials, and multiple runspaces. Function supports custom timeout parameters in case of wmi problems and returns from the registry program name, manufacturer, and uninstall information. You can view verbose information on each runspace thread in realtime with the -Verbose option.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multithreaded HP Server Health Check with Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/08/22/multithreaded-hp-server-health-check-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 17:32:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/08/22/multithreaded-hp-server-health-check-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This function attempts to query the HP WBEM WMI provider information to ascertain the general health of a physical server. By default just the general health status is returned. Optionally you can include the following components in the results: ethernet teams, array controllers , ethernet adapters, fans, HBAs, power supplies, and temperature sensors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multithreaded Remote Registry Gathering with Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/08/06/multithreaded-remote-registry-gathering-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 03:11:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/08/06/multithreaded-remote-registry-gathering-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Gather specific subkey values or an entire registry key’s subkey values with powershell and multithreading.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multithreaded System Asset Gathering with Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/08/05/multithreaded-system-asset-gathering-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 17:35:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/08/05/multithreaded-system-asset-gathering-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This function gathers a plethora of useful system information via WMI and multithreading with powershell.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2010 Mailbox Audit Report GUI</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/28/exchange-2010-mailbox-audit-report-gui/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 20:17:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/28/exchange-2010-mailbox-audit-report-gui/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve updated the original &lt;a href=&#34;https://zacharyloeber.com/2013/05/09/exchange-2010-mailbox-audit-report-script/&#34;&gt;Exchange Mailbox Audit Report Script&lt;/a&gt; with some new features and bug fixes. These updates have also set the stage for the entire script to be wrapped with a GUI! Here is the initial release of the Mailbox Audit Report GUI for your auditing needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Enhanced Remote Server Connectivity Testing With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/25/enhanced-remote-server-connectivity-testing-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 14:22:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/25/enhanced-remote-server-connectivity-testing-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Test the following connectivity methods to a server: RDP, ping, rpc, wsman, sccm agent, scom agent, and remote registry. Optionally an alternate credential can be used. Versatility is added with options to return only true/false when singular tests are performed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Use Powershell to Gather Disk/Partition/Mount Point Information</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/23/use-powershell-to-gather-diskpartitionmount-point-information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 04:41:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/23/use-powershell-to-gather-diskpartitionmount-point-information/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I put together a function for remotely gathering Windows disk information. This was specifically written to accommodate alternate credentials. This script also accounts for the glaring disconnect between win32_Volume and win32_DiskDrive within WMI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Audit User Profile Folders With Powershell</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/21/audit-user-profile-folders-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 18:46:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/21/audit-user-profile-folders-with-powershell/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This function will aggregate sub-folders within a folder on a server and attempt to associate them with user IDs within a domain and provide additional information. This script can also be used to move folders for disabled or non-existent accounts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Book Review: PowerShell 3.0 Advanced Administration Handbook</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/18/book-review-powershell-3-0-advanced-administration-handbook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2013 01:44:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/18/book-review-powershell-3-0-advanced-administration-handbook/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A fast-paced PowerShell guide with real-world scenarios and detailed solutions&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Use Powershell to Create a Windows Service Dependency Diagrams</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/17/use-powershell-to-create-a-windows-service-dependency-diagrams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 15:32:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/17/use-powershell-to-create-a-windows-service-dependency-diagrams/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I use powershell with graphviz to generate color coded service dependency diagrams for windows services. Besides creating useful and beautiful diagrams for your environment, this will also provide some interesting functions for gathering remote service information with alternate credentials.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell Utility: Comment Based Help Automater</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/02/powershell-utility-comment-based-help-automater/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 20:05:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/06/02/powershell-utility-comment-based-help-automater/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Comment based help is used in powershell-land to provide fast and easy help for cmdlets at the console. This little powershell based GUI helps fellow coders automatically construct comment based help blocks for their functions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2010 Mailbox Audit Report Script</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/05/09/exchange-2010-mailbox-audit-report-script/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 02:33:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/05/09/exchange-2010-mailbox-audit-report-script/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;exchange-2010-mailbox-audit-report-script&#34;&gt;Exchange 2010 Mailbox Audit Report Script&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve released a number of scripts such as the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/Colorize-HTML-Table-Cells-2ea63acd&#34;&gt;HTML Table Colorizer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/Get-Exchange-Calendar-5bb4f527&#34;&gt;Exchange Mailbox Calendar Permission Function&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gallery.technet.microsoft.com/Exchange-Mailbox-GUI-5b204590&#34;&gt;Exchange Mailbox GUI&lt;/a&gt;. These were all actually created specifically as support scripts for a report generation powershell tool I’ve been working on, the Exchange Mailbox Auditing Tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Powershell: Colorize-Table.ps1 Updated</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/04/28/powershell-colorize-table-ps1-updated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 18:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/04/28/powershell-colorize-table-ps1-updated/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A little while ago I released a script which uses custom linq assemblies to quickly modify an html table based on column header and an arbitrary scriptblock to test the values within that entire column (by default it is a simple -eq comparison). If the scriptblock evaluates to be true then you can either change just the cell style or the entire row style.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exchange: Co-existence Client Access Preparation Report</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/01/15/exchange-co-existence-client-access-preparation-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2013 03:36:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2013/01/15/exchange-co-existence-client-access-preparation-report/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you upgrade Exchange in a co-existence scenario (you want to keep the same client access namespace) there is one crucial moment of truth which must be overcome. This is the phase of the migration I&amp;#8217;ve come to call the &amp;#8220;dns flip-over&amp;#8221; or the &amp;#8220;client access part&amp;#8221;. Without preparation this part of the migration can be a real headache as issues are directly experienced by your end users.  This is a simple report card you can use to prepare you for this moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Create Your Own Network Assessment Appliance: Additional Tools</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2012/11/28/create-your-own-network-assessment-appliance-additional-tools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 02:24:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2012/11/28/create-your-own-network-assessment-appliance-additional-tools/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;https://zacharyloeber.com/2012/04/08/create-your-own-network-assessment-appliance/&#34; title=&#34;Create your own network assessment appliance&#34;&gt;previously did a write up&lt;/a&gt; on a personal virtual machine I like to keep at hand for performing network analysis and discovery. I&amp;#8217;ve since added a few tools to the VM and documented how they were installed so I figured I&amp;#8217;d share on how it was done. Even if you don&amp;#8217;t setup everything in this post it may be worthwhile to glance through it for some network engineering tools which are free to setup and use but not highly publicized. Anyone who cares to read this post has likely heard of Solarwinds but I highly doubt you have heard of all the tools in this list (let alone how to set them up). Regardless, I&amp;#8217;ll start with a tool anyone worth their salt has heard of though, Cacti&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exchange 2010: Poor Mans Monitoring 1.5</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2012/08/27/exchange-2010-poor-mans-monitoring-1-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2012 02:40:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2012/08/27/exchange-2010-poor-mans-monitoring-1-5/</guid><description>Just a quick upgrade to the script I posted earlier. This script is for monitoring and/or maintaining your Exchange 2010 mailboxes. It is meant to help an admin be proactive in their exchange environment. I updated the script to be a bit more customizable and fixed some obvious issues. The primary changes are removing the requirement for the MS chart controls as well as introducing an area of code just for custom scripts.</description></item><item><title>Lync 2010: IP/DNS Workbook</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2012/06/23/lync-2010-ipdns-workbook/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2012 20:24:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2012/06/23/lync-2010-ipdns-workbook/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I just ran across &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.technet.com/b/nexthop/archive/2011/12/07/useful-tips-for-testing-your-lync-edge-server.aspx&#34; title=&#34;Useful Tips For Testing Your Lync Edge Server&#34;&gt;a Lync article&lt;/a&gt; with all kinds of nice tables which distilled the myriad of DNS/IP addresses in a Lync deployment down to an easy to read format. I happen to have created one of these tables myself for a Lync deployment which included a standard Lync pool, XMPP gateway, Lync Mobility, and a single edge server. I figured others may find some use from it as it auto-populates the dns entries and what they are supposed to point to based on what you fill out for the highlighted cells. Sure you get some of this in the Lync Server 2010 Planning Tool but this offers a slightly different view of the environment as well as a nice one page overview.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Create Your Own Network Assessment Appliance</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2012/04/08/create-your-own-network-assessment-appliance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:49:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2012/04/08/create-your-own-network-assessment-appliance/</guid><description>In this write-up I setup several network assessment tools which can be used in the discovery process of a new environment. This can be useful for a newly hired sysadmin or a consultant in rapidly gathering information to assess the health and/or state of a network.
Introduction I often find myself assessing a foreign network infrastructure for performance or other issues. Depending on the size of the environment, digesting everything can be daunting without the help of some third party tools.</description></item><item><title>Windows: 2003 to 2008 R2 RADIUS Migration</title><link>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2011/03/17/windows-2003-to-2008-r2-radius-migration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2011 12:58:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zacharyloeber.com/blog/2011/03/17/windows-2003-to-2008-r2-radius-migration/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I found myself doing yet another Windows 2003 IAS Radius server migration to 2008 R2 NPS. I found that I had my prior notes and was able to do this quickly but, hell, if I&amp;#8217;m looking this up in my own notes I may as well just post this succinct little procedure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>